Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
Julius Epstein Papers,
1939-1975
75063
Epstein, Julius, 1901-
194 manuscript boxes, 16 oversize boxes, 1 envelope (87.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, photographs, and printed matter, relating to World War II, communism, forced repatriation of Russian prisoners to the Soviet Union following World War II, the Katyn forest massacre, unreported deaths of Soviet cosmonauts, and the efforts of J. Epstein to obtain restricted government documents on these subjects.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Astronauts--Soviet Union.; Communism.; Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940.; Official secrets--United States.; Prisoners of war.; Security classification (Government documents)--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Atrocities.; World War, 1939-1945--Forced repatriation.; World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons.; World War, 1939-1945--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); United States--Foreign relations.
Biographical Note
1901 Born, Vienna, Austria
Studied economics and political science at the universities of Jena and Leipzig
Free-lance journalist
1939 Came to the United States
1941-1945 Worked for the Office of War Information
Correspondent for several European newspapers
1963 Research Associate, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1972 Professor of International Affairs, Lincoln University, San Francisco
1974 Author, Operation Keelhaul: The Story of Forced Repatriation
1975 Died, Menlo Park, California
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 1-86.)
  Reports, memoranda, letters, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Aachen (Box 1)
  - Abd El Krim
  - Abdullah, King of Trans-Jordan
  - Abend, Hallett, "Beware of S-Day"
  - "A-bomb"
  - "Abundance"
  - Acheson-Lilienthal Atomic Energy Report
  - Acheson, Dean
    - General
    - Abandons China
    - Appointed Secretary of State
    - "The Case against Dean Acheson," by Julius Epstein, further referred to as J. E.
    - Criticized as Secretary of State
    - On Franco-Spain
    - "Freedom's Case against Dean Acheson"
    - "The Illusion of Disengagement," by Dean Acheson
    - Letter to the father of a marine
    - Mandel's memorandum
    - Policy as Secretary of State
    - Statement on Alger Hiss
  - "Achtundvierziger" - immigration question
  - Adenauer, Konrad
    - General
    - Government
    - And Khrushchev
    - Triumph
    - In Washington, 1957
  - Advertisements
  - Advertisements (Box 2)
  - 'Advertising Kitty'
  - Africa
  - Africa, The New
  - African Guide 1962
  - African States (new ones)
  - Agh, Laszlo Imre, Captain
  - Aid to Greece and Turkey
  - Air power
  - Airborne alert
  - Airlines
  - Aktion Walkure
  - Alaska
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Clippings
    - "Der deutsche Alaska Plan" (the German Alaska Plan, J. E.)
    - "Erwiderung" (answer)
    - J. E.'s statement on Alaska statehood
  - Albania
  - Aleman, Manuel Jose (theft in Cuba) (Box 3)
  - Alibis
  - Allgemeine Hinweise
  - Alliance for Liberation and Freedom in Czechoslovakia
  - Allied generals
  - Alsop, Joseph
  - Alsop, Joseph and Stewart
  - Alsop, Stewart
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Interview with John F. Kennedy
    - Vs. Johnson, Louis
  - Alter, Victor. See Erlich, Henryk
  - Ambruster, Howard Watson (opposes the rearming of Germany)
  - Amerasia
  - American Anti-Communist League
  - American Association for a Democratic Germany
  - American Counsel for Judaism
  - American fascism
  - American Federation of Labor
    - General
    - Against Stalin
  - American Fellow Travelers
  - American foreign policy (Department of State publication)
  - American-German Conference, 1961
  - American Indians
  - American Institute for the Study of Non-Military Warfare
  - American Jewish Committee
  - American Jewish Conference
  - American Jewish Congress
  - American Jewish League Against Communism, Inc., 2 folders)
  - American Legion
  - American Nation's Security Pact
  - American Press
  - American Radio
  - American Reports, Inc.
  - American Rocket Society
  - American Russian Institute
  - American State Hospitals
  - Americans for Intellectual Freedom
  - Americans in Germany
  - America's shame (Louisiana Child Aid rules)
  - Amery, John
  - Anaconda Wire
  - Anders, Wladyslaw, General
  - Andriyve, E. (Eastland witness)
  - Angell, Norman
  - Anglo-Russian 20 Year Treaty
  - Antarctica
  - Anti-Comintern Pact
  - Anti-Communist Community Action
  - Anti-Nazi League
  - Anti-Semitism
    - "A Threat to Democracy"
    - In Russia
  - Anti-Strike Bill (Senate version)
  - Aosta, Duke of
  - A & P
  - App, Austin, "History's Most Terrifying Peace"
  - Arab "Palestine Government" (Box 4)
  - Arab populations
  - Arab propaganda of the Nazis
  - Arabia
  - Arabs on Palestine
  - Aramco
  - Araquistain, Luis (on Soviet policy towards Republican Spain)
  - Archbishop of York
  - Arciszewski, Tomasz, "Poland - A Test Case"
  - Arctic
  - Argentina
  - Arkadiev, Georgi
  - Armenians, Soviet. See Soviet Armenians
  - Armistice Italy-Allies
  - Army document, Communist propaganda inserted in
  - Army insignia (U.S.A.)
  - Army talk
  - Arnold, Henry H. - Report
  - Arski, Stefan, "The New Polish-German Border"
  - Associated Press
  - "Atlantic Union"
  - Atomic achievements in France
  - Atomic energy
    - And American policy
    - Commission
    - Control of (UN document)
    - International control
    - For peace
  - Atomic plane
  - Attlee, Clement
  - Auer, Theodor M.
  - Aufbau
    - "Achtung Lebensgefahr"
    - "Kriegsziele"
  - Aufhauser, S., "Der Sowjet-russische Propagandakrieg gegen die Vereinigten Staaten"
  - Aurora Verlag
  - Auschwitz - Birkenau concentration camps
  - Austin, Warren
  - Australia
  - Austria
  - Austrian American Tribune
  - Austrian Battalion
  - Austrian hymn
  - Austrian puppet
  - Austrian State Treaty
  - Axis spies in the U.S.
  - Babuk, Wladimir - Landow, Wladimir (Russian immigrant, arrived in N.Y. in 1949)
  - Badoglio, Petro (Box 5)
  - Balchen, Bernt
  - Baldwin, Hanson W.
  - Baldwin, Roger
  - Ball, Joseph Hurst, Senator
  - Baltic States (in John Foster Dulles's opinion)
  - Baltic tragedy
  - Baltimore Sun papers
  - Bank hold-ups
  - Barmine, Alexander, "The New Communist Conspiracy"
  - Barnes, Joseph
  - Barsov (Russian flyer)
  - Barth, Max
  - Baruch, Bernard M.
  - Basseches, Nikolaus, "U.S.S.R."
  - Basler National-Zeitung (clippings)
  - Baumgartner, Josef, Dr.
  - Bavarian Constitution
  - Becher, Johannes (letter from son)
  - Beer, Max, "Geheimbericht an Goebbels"
  - Behind the Iron Curtain (newsletter)
  - Begin, Menachem
  - Belgium
  - Belgo-Congolese Round Table Conference
  - Ben Bella interview
  - Belsen concentration camp
  - Ben-Gurion, David
    - General
    - Loyalty to Israel
  - Benelux
  - Benes, Eduard
    - General
    - And the Soviets
    - Interview with Roosevelt on Baltic States
    - Memoirs
    - Political statement
  - Benes-Stalin (Sulzberger article)
  - Benson, Ezra Taft
  - Berchtold, Leopold, Graf
  - Berdyaev, Nicolas
  - Berendsen, Carl (New Zealand)
  - Beria, Lavrenti P. (official indictment)
  - Berle, A. A., Jr.
    - General
    - Hiss - Chambers affair
  - Berlin, Irving
  - Berlin
    - American broadcasts
    - Conference, 1954
    - Crisis, 1961
    - Legal situation
    - Refugees
  - Bermuda Plan
  - Bess, Demaree
  - Bessenyey, Gabor de, Dr.
  - Beveridge Plan
  - Bevin, Ernest
    - General
    - Cable to
  - Bibliographical notes
  - Bidault, Georges
  - Biddle, Francis (report on Nuremberg) (Box 6)
  - Bilbo, Theodore G.
  - Bilmanis, Alfred
  - Bing, Inc.
  - Biological warfare
  - Birch Society
  - Birkenau - Auschwitz concentration camps. See Auschwitz
  - Bisbee, Brigadier General
  - Bissell, Clayton L.
    - Biographical data
    - Hearing of Feb. 27, 1945
    - Hearing of June 3, 1952
    - In connection with McCloy
    - Photograph
  - "The Last Days of the Bismarck"
  - Blockade (manuscripts)
  - Blueprints
  - Boas, Franz
  - Bogolepov, Jgor
  - Bogota
    - Charter
    - Conference, 1948
    - Uprising, 1948
  - Bonn Constitution
  - 'Book burning', 2 folders)
  - Book-of-the-Month Club
  - Boothe, Luce Clare
    - General
    - Broadcasts
  - Bor-Komorowski, T.
  - Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio
  - Borin, V. L., "The Russian Underground Conquered the World"
  - Bormann, Martin
  - Boswell, James
  - Braden, Spruille
  - Bradley, Omar N.
  - Brandl publications
  - Brandt, Albert A.
  - Brandt, Willy
  - Brauchitsch, Walther von (Box 7)
  - Brazil
  - Brendonck concentration camp
  - Brentano, Heinrich von
  - Brewster, Owen, "10 Years of Secrecy in Our China Policy"
  - Bridges, Style (speech of July 18, 1950)
  - Bricker Amendment
  - British Cabinet (March 1, 1950)
  - British Empire
  - British Empire's vital points
  - British fellow-travelers
  - British Library of Information
  - British report on Hitler's death
  - British-Siamese Peace Treaty
  - British spy (for the Germans)
  - British war production
  - British White Paper on India
  - Brkich, Dushan
  - Broadcasts to Germany
  - Bromfield, Louis
  - Brown, John, "Deutschtum and America"
  - "Bruderschaft"
  - Bruning, Heinrich
  - Bryukhonenko, Serge
  - Buchenwald concentration camp
  - Buck, Pearl S.
  - Burgers, Anna
  - Bukar, Jan (witness before the Committee on Un-American Activities)
  - Bulgaria
    - Anti-Axis revolt in Sofia, 1943
    - Armistice, 1944
    - Tensions within
  - Bulletin, German Republic, 2 folders)
  - Bullitt, William C., 7 folders)
  - Bulow, Bernhard von
  - Bumke, Erwin
  - Busbey, Frederick E.
  - Bush, Vannevar (address of April 3, 1951)
  - Byelorussia and Ukraine in the UN
  - Byrnes, James F.
  - Cagliari Debate
  - Calomiris, Angela
  - Camouflaged communist press
  - Campbell, Francis Stuart, "Credo of a Reactionary"
  - Canada
    - General
    - "Canada 1946" (Box 8)
    - Fear of invasion
    - House of Commons debates, June 27, 1946
    - Journal American supplement, "Souce of Strength for a Free World"
    - Official Handbook, 1945
    - War production
  - Canadian Information Service
  - Canadian Intelligence Service
  - Canadian Spy Inquiry
  - Cancer chart
  - Cannibalism, tribalism, witch craft
  - Canterbury, Dean of (Reverend Hewlett Johnson)
  - Capehart on Hiss trial
  - Carol, former king of Romania
  - Carroll, Wallace, "It Takes a Russian to Beat a Russian"
  - Carretta, Donato
  - Castro, Fidel - Cuban crisis
  - Catholic Association for International Peace
  - Catholic Welfare Conference
  - Catholics
  - Celler, "Let Exiles Enter U.S. as Visitors"
  - Chamberlin, William H.
  - Chambrun, Count de
  - Chautemps, Camille
  - "Chef"
  - Chemical warfare
  - Chennault, Claire Lee
  - Cherne, Leo, "How to Spot a Communist"
  - The Chicago Sun
  - Chile
  - Chiang Kai-shek
    - General
    - Interview with M. Higgins
    - New Campaign, Summer 1953
    - State Department officials on file
  - China
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Famine
    - Maurer report
    - Polit Bureau
    - Presents her case to the United Nations
    - U.S. White Paper, August 1949
  - The China Magazine
  - Chinese Civil War
  - Chinese communists and Moscow (Box 9)
  - Chinese communists take Nanking
  - Chinese revolution
  - Chinese-Russian Treaty
  - Christian opposition in the Third Reich
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Christianform
  - Chungsoon, Kwak
  - Church of the Healing Christ
  - Churchill, Randolph
  - Churchill, Winston, Sir
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Atlantic Charter
    - Biographical dates
    - On Bulgaria and Stalin
    - Denial of any intentions to go through the Balkans
    - On F.D.R. and the Badoglio regime
    - On Rudolf Hess
    - Invasion of the Continent
    - Meetings with Stalin, October 1944
    - Opposition to
    - Quotes, 2 folders)
    - Rearming of Nazis against Soviets
    - The Second World War - Memoirs
      - New York Times, 3 folders)
      - Life, 2 folders)
    - Speeches
      - General
      - Boston speech, March 31, 1949
      - Before Congress, January 17, 1952
      - On Palestine
      - Pan-Europe speech
      - On War with the U.S.S.R.
    - Note to Stalin
  - The Churchman (Box 10)
    - General
    - Birkhead memorandum
    - Common Cause release
    - Dinner, 1949
    - Documents Shipler sent in reply to Gotshal
    - Shipler's letter to Gotshal
    - Woltman's articles on Churchman Dinner, 1949
  - Churchmen who defy Hitler
  - CIA
    - General, 2 folders)
    - 1962
    - The Nation, special issue
  - Ciano, Count
  - CIO Report on Soviet Labor
  - Clergy, Red infiltration into
  - The Clinton Recorder
  - Clippings. See General clippings
  - Civil aviation
  - Civil Service Commission
  - Clapper, Raymond
  - Clodius, Karl
  - Coal strike
  - Cobb, Irvin S.
  - Cocteau, Jean
  - Cohn, Roy M.
  - Coleman (Kallmann)
  - College communism
  - Collier's Third World War
  - Columbia University (Soviet propaganda films)
  - Comintell
  - Comintern, 2 folders)
  - Committee on Soviet Seizure of the Baltic States
  - Common Cause
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Carnegie Hall Rally, May 5, 1949
  - Common Council for American Unity
  - "Communism a World Menace"
  - "Communism in Action", 2 folders)
  - Communism in the U.S., 2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Communist anti-semitism
  - Communist block
    - Expansion, 1939-1961
    - Military strength, 1961
  - Communist general line (changes, Moscow)
  - Communist Party (U.S.A.)
  - Communist vote and representation in governments in Europe
  - Communists
    - In America (Jackson Papers)
    - In Germany
    - In Japan
  - "Communists within the Government"
  - Conditions in Occupied Territories
  - Condon, Edward U., Dr.
  - Connally Anti-Strike Bill
  - Conscientious objectors
  - Contests
  - Concentration camps in the U.S.
  - Conference on German Peace (Lipschutz)
  - Conference of Teheran
  - Congo, Republic of
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom
  - Congress' power to declare war
  - Congressional Committees, 1951
  - Congressional Record (regulations)
  - Constitution of the U.S.
  - Contact Book, 2 folders)
  - Controversies
  - Cook, Thos. & Sons
  - Cooper, Kent
  - Coplon, Judith
  - Correction marks
  - Cost of World War II
  - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Count
  - Council of Foreign Ministers
  - Council on Foreign Relations
  - Count of Paris
  - Counterattack, 3 folders)
  - Courths-Mahler, Hedwig
  - Crankshaw, Edward
  - Crawford, Frederick C. (on France under Nazis)
  - Creel, George, "What We Will Do with Germany"
  - Crime inquiry (by U.S. Senate) (Box 12)
  - Crimea
  - Croce, Benedetto, 2 folders)
  - Crosby, Bing. See Bing, Inc.
  - Crown Prince Friedrich Wilhelm, 2 folders)
  - Cuba
    - Anti-Castro declaration
    - Cardona's statement
    - Crisis, 1962
    - Failure
    - Invasion of
    - Statement (State Department)
  - Culbertson, Ely
  - Current Soviet thought
  - Curzon Line, 2 folders)
  - Cyprus Agreement
  - Czapski, M. Joseph (on Starobielsk)
  - Czech chauvinism
  - Czech elections, 1948
  - Czech opposition to Benes
  - Czech opposition to Gottwaldt?
  - Czech Government in Exile
  - Czechel, John
  - Czechoslovakia, 2 folders)
  - Czernin, Ferdinand, Count
  - Dali, Salvador, 2 folders)
  - Dallin, David J.
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Forced Labor statement - UN
  - Daniell, Raymond
  - Dante's Inferno - Song III 22-51 (translation by Stefan George)
  - Dardanelles, 2 folders)
  - Darlan, Francois
  - Data. See general data
  - Davies, Joseph E., 2 folders)
  - Davis, Chester C.
  - Dean, Vera Micheles
    - General, 2 folders)
    - "Catalogue of Errors"
    - Madeira Report
    - Own Report (J. E.)
    - Reviews of her books (Box 13)
    - Standard-Times article, 2 folders)
  - Deat, Marcel
  - Declaration of Independence
  - Decline of American foreign policy
  - Delaney Broadcast
  - Demands for territory
  - Democracy
  - Democratic Platform, 1960 (Los Angeles)
  - Demokratische Post
  - Denikin, A. (concerning forceful repatriation of Soviet prisoners)
  - Dennen, Leon, "The Soviet Peace Myth"
  - Denny, Harold
  - Denny, Ludwell
  - Department of State
    - Diplomatic lists, 1950-1951
    - Economic policy towards Germany
    - Foreign Aid Program
    - Foreign policy
      - General
      - "Our Foreign Policy"
    - Foreign service
      - General
      - List, April 1, 1948
    - Displaced persons
    - Freedom of Information
    - Loyalty and security programs
    - Occupation of Germany (Box 14)
    - Press releases
    - Publications
      - General, 3 folders)
      - On foreign policy
    - Releases, 2 folders)
    - Registers
      - 1946
      - 1948 (Box 15)
    - Report on International Control of Atomic Energy
    - Round Table Discussion on American Policy Towards China, October 1949
    - Telephone directory, 2 folders)
    - White Book, September 1948
  - Detective agencies
  - Detroit Golden Jubilae
  - Deutsch, Harold C. (from the series "Hitler's Deal with Stalin")
  - Deutsch, Julius
  - Deutsche Gegenwart
  - Deutsche Tageszeitungen
  - Deutsche Vereine
  - Deutsches Radio in die U.S.A.
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
    - General
    - Campaign speeches, 2 folders)
    - Message to the legislature
  - Dieppe
  - Dies, Martin, 2 folders)
  - Diplomatic Missions in Germany (Box 16)
  - Disarmament
  - Diseases
  - Disintegration
    - Material
    - Memorandum
  - Dismantling
    - General
    - In Germany
    - List
  - Displaced persons
    - General
    - Department of State publication
  - Diverse manuscripts
  - Divine, Father
  - Divorce in the U.S.
  - Dodecanese
  - Dog-case
  - Dohrn, Klaus
    - Memoranda to, from Julius Epstein
  - Dondero, George
  - Dope
    - Cases
    - Congressional records
  - Doolittle, James H.
  - Doriot, Jacques
  - Douglas, William O., 2 folders)
  - Doussinague, Jose (Memoirs)
  - DP Law - Immigration Program
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Dreyfus, Alfred
  - Drug control under the UN
  - Dryfoos, Orvil E.
  - Dubinsky, David
  - Duke of Windsor
  - Dulles, John Foster
    - General, 2 folders)
    - On peace with Japan
    - Speeches
      - General
      - April 22, 1957 (on liberation)
    - Statement, March 1954
  - Dumbarton Oaks (Box 17)
  - Dunkirk
  - Dupont de Nemours
  - Dutch-Indonesian Agreement
  - Duttweiler, Gottlieb
  - East Asia
  - "East Germany under Soviet Control"
  - East-West trade
  - Eastland, James O.
  - Eastman, Max
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Material delivered on October 11, 1947
  - Economic Cooperation Administration
  - Economic Stability Act, 1949
  - The Economist
  - Editorials
  - Egypt
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya, 2 folders)
  - Ehrlich, David P.
  - Eichmann, Adolf
    - Before the UN
    - SS General
    - Trial
      - Documents
      - Editorial opinion
      - Releases by Jewish organizations
      - Verdict and sentences
  - Eight Colonels Paper
  - Einsiedel, Count von
  - Einstein, Albert
    - General
    - Writings against him
  - Einzelne Belege
  - Eire ("Ireland's Rulers")
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - On Berlin (December 1961)
    - Foreign policy speech, September 23, 1952
    - Hopkins's quotation
    - Letter to Bulganin, February 15, 1958
    - Memoirs
    - "As Pegler Sees It"
    - Press conference, April 9, 1958
    - On socialists in civil service
  - Eliot, George Fielding, 2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Elliot, William Yandell
  - Emmet, Christopher
  - Empire Trust Letter
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica
  - Enemy aliens
  - "England und USA - Schrittmacher des Bolschewismus"
  - "England, Wartime"
  - English manuscripts by Julius Epstein
  - "English vs. American Newspapers"
  - Entwurfe
  - Epstein, Klaus
  - Erlich, Henryk and Alter, Victor
  - Ermachtigungsgesetz
  - Ershov, Wassili
  - European boundaries since 115 A.D.
  - European misery
  - "European Recovery"
  - Euthanasia
  - Evans, William H.
  - Events leading up to World War II
  - Excerpts, 2 folders)
  - Expellees
  - Facts on file (Box 19)
  - Falkenhorst, Nikolaus von
  - Farmer, Fyke
  - Farrell, James T., "Vishinsky, Moscow Purge and Nuremberg"
  - "Fascism in Action," U.S. official publication, 2 folders)
  - Father Brown
  - Federation of Former Communists
  - "F.D.R. Was Well Warned before He Recognized the Soviet Goverment" (by J. E.)
  - F.D.R.'s 'homework'
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation
  - "Feed the Germans"
  - Feiler, Arthur
  - Feller, Abraham
  - Field, Fred Vanderbilt
  - Fighting French Proposal to Giraud
  - Finland, 3 folders)
    - Bevin, on Finland
    - In 1949
  - Finnish-Jewish question (and duplicates)
  - Finnish Jews during the war (2 folders and reprints)
  - Finnish newspapers in the U.S.
  - The Firing Line (American Legion)
  - First air bombardments
  - Fischer, Louis
  - Fischer, Markoosha
  - Fischer, Ruth, 3 folders)
    - Life article of May 8, 1950
    - On her book
  - Fischer, John
  - Fischer, Max
  - Fish Armstrong, Hamilton
  - Flood, Daniel J.
  - Fluegge, Rudolph
  - Flying saucers
  - Flynn, John T.
  - Foch, Ferdinand, 2 folders)
  - Foerster, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 20)
  - Folkmann, General
  - Food and Agriculture Organization (UN)
  - Ford, Henri
  - Foreign agents
    - 1951
    - 1953
    - 1960
  - Foreign Aid Program
  - Foreign broadcasts (Foreign Broadcasts Information Service), 4 folders)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 21)
    - Bulletin
    - And Carnegie Foundation
    - Crop 1954
    - Diverse material
    - Dean, Vera Micheles
      - Broadcasts
      - The case against
    - Material for the article
    - New research, 1953
    - Papers
    - Prospects (Box 22)
    - Report (rough draft)
    - Reports
  - Formosa
  - Forrestal, James
    - Death 'explanations'
    - Huie, William Bradford - Articles
  - "Forum on the Air," March 4, 1947
  - 11. Forum, New York Herald Tribune
  - 12. Forum
  - Foster, William Z.
    - General
    - Before the Dies Committee
    - Before Congressional Committee
    - "The New Europe"
  - Fotitch-Krek memorandum
  - France
    - General
    - In three invasions, 2 folders)
    - Occupied
    - Welles on her importance
  - France's Occupation Forces in Germany
  - Franco, Francisco
    - General
    - Higgins' interview
    - Regime - Spain
  - Frank, Hans
  - Franklin, Jay, "Harry Truman's Foreign Policy"
  - Free Austria
  - Free Belgians (Box 23)
  - Free Czechoslovaks
  - Free Danes
  - Free Europe Declaration
  - Free France
  - Free French
  - Free German Committee (London, Moscow)
  - Free Germans
    - General
    - London
  - Free Germany
    - General
    - "Neues Deutschland"
    - Mexico
  - Free Greeks
  - 'Free Hungarian' government at Debrecen
  - Free Italians
  - 'Free Japan' League
  - Free Netherlands
  - Free Norway
  - Free Poland
  - Free Rumania
  - Free Russia Movement, 1949
  - Free Yugoslavians
  - "Free World" - Honorary Board
  - Frei, Bruno
  - Fremde manuskripte (foreign manuscripts)
  - French Committee of National Liberation
  - French Copyright Theft